Sis, come on! You'd better get out of bed!
お姉ちゃん  そろそろ起きないと…
Sis-?!
お姉ちゃ…
It's eight! I'm late!
はッ ８時！
ちッ 遅刻 遅刻ッ
Hey, you. Why the rush?
何で急ぐの？
See you later!
ちこく～ッ
Oh, good morning, Yui.
あら 唯ちゃん
Good morning!
おはよ～
Wha...?
あれ？ 見間違えた～
I read the clock wrong!
Starting today--
今日から…
I'm a high schooler!
高校生！
TRIPPIN' OUT
Chatting Now
ガチでカシマシ　Never Ending Girls' Talk
You're really noisy
Never ending,
it can't stop!
I can't wait until the bell rings at the end of class
a
終業チャイムまで待てない
Being late is fine
遅刻はしても早退はNon Non Non!
But leaving early is a no-no!
a
精一杯Study After School
I'll study hard after school
a
ドキドキが止まんない　フルスロットルな脳内
My heart won't stop thumping
Going full throttle is suicidal
希望·欲望·煩悩　リボンかけて包装
Hope
Desire
Trouble
Wrap them all up with a ribbon
ネタどっさり持ち寄り　New　Type　Version打ち込み
I'll gather lots of machinery
and I'll program the version n times
男子禁制のプリ帳　恋綴った日記帳
I have a photo album without guys,
but there are actually some in it
スカート丈2cm　詰めたら跳ぶよ
I'll cut my skirt
by 2 centimeters
and I'll be at the top
昨日より遠く　おとといよりオクターブ高く
Further than yesterday
I'll reach a higher octave than the day before
a
Jumping
out
Jumping Now
ガチでウルワシ　Never Ending Girls' Life
It's beautiful
Never ending,
I can fly!
日々マジ　ライブだし待ったなし
Playing live at lunch? Cancel it!
a
早起きしても早寝はNon Non Non!
Getting
up early
is fine,
but going
to bed early
is a no-no!
a
Fight with all we've got
目一杯Shouting　わっしょい
Hooray!
a
ガチでスバラシ　Never Ending Girls' Song
It's splendid
Never ending
It can't stop!
午後ティータイムには持ってこい
The afternoon teatime is perfect
a
片思いでも玉砕でHere we go!
My unrequited love will be defeated
a
But here I go!
歌えばShining After School
I'll sing for you
a
After school
Congratulations on starting school here!
入学おめでとうございま～す
Please join the tennis club!
ぜひ テニス部へ
ぜひ 柔道部へ
The Judo Club's better!
ぜひ 茶道部へ
Please join the Tea Ceremony Club!
Please join the Abacus!
ぜひ 珠算部へ
ぜひの ぜひ！
Please! Please!
Come on!
What are you groaning about, Yui?
何うなってるのよ 唯
Oh, hello, Nodoka.
あッ 和ちゃ～ん
I'm not sure which club I should join in.
実はどの部活に入ろうか迷って…
What? You haven't decided on one?
えッ まだ決めてなかったの？
もう 学校始まってから２週間も たってるよ
It's already been two weeks since school started. You have to choose!
But I'm absolutely terrible at every sport, and I don't really get any of the literary clubs.
でもでも 私 運動オンチだし
文化系のクラブもよく分かんないし
こうやってニートが出来上がっていくのね
This is how people end up becoming NEETs.
You're pegged as a NEET just 'cause you don't join a club?
部活やってないだけでニート!?
You know, looking back on it, for as long as I've known you, you've never joined a single club, have you?
振り返ってみると
唯って今まで 何の部活もやってこなかったもんね
ニー…ニー…ニー…ト…
Crud!
グサッ！
I really do feel like I ought to at least try to do something.
何かしなくちゃ いけないような気がするんだけど…
But what the heck should I be doing?
一体 何をすればいいんだろ～う
Club Suspended!
Mio!
澪～ッ
Ritsu?
律
Let's go check out the club!
クラブ見学 行こうぜ
Which club do you mean?
クラブ見学？
The Light Music Club! What do you think?
軽音部だよ 軽音部
でも私 文芸部に入るつもりだし
But I was planning on joining the Literature Club.
えッ？
I've already filled out the application form.
入部希望の紙も書いたし
Rip.
ビリッ
ああーッ 何すんのよ 律！
What do you think you're doing?
Come on, let's go! Move it, move it!
ほ～ら 行くぞ 早く早く～
Cut it out!
ちょっと～
Huh? It's disbanded?!
えッ 廃部した？
Well, on the verge of being disbanded.
正確には 廃部寸前ね
All the students who were in the club last year have now graduated,
昨年度までいた部員はみんな卒業しちゃって
今月中に４人 入部しないと 廃部になっちゃうの
so the club will be disbanded unless four students join this month.
だから 誰もいなかったんだ 音楽室
So that's why there wasn't anyone in the Music Room...
Miss Yamanaka!
先生～
Hi, Yui. I'll be right there.
はい 今 行くわね
ごめんね 次 音楽の授業あるから
I'm sorry, I have a music class to teach in a few minutes.
Light Music Club, good luck!
頑張ってね 軽音部
She sure was pretty, wasn't she?
キレイな先生だったなあ
That is not the issue here.
そういう問題じゃねえ
Please hand out the syllabus sheets to all the students.
このプリントをみんなに配っておいてね
The syllabus sheets?
プリントを…？
Oh, right! So sorry about that!
あッ は はい 失礼いたしやした
They're staring at me!
にらまれたッ
Bad tempo.
テンポ悪…
Oh, no!
She's useless.
しッ しまった
使えない子
I-I'm so sorry!
すッ すみません
大丈夫？
Are you all right?
And clumsy.
ドジっ子…
It's being disbanded, so that's that. I'm gonna go join the Literature Club.
廃部なら しかたないな
私は文芸部に…
If I join and there aren't any members, does that make me the club president?
誰も いないってことは
今 入部すれば 私が部長？
Doesn't sound bad at all!
悪くないわね～
What was that club you were talking about with those girls?
あの さっき話してた軽音部って？
The Light Music Club?
軽音部？
Yeah, what is it?
って何ですか？
The Light Music Club is about playing lighthearted music.
「軽い音楽」と書いて「軽音」よ
Light Music Club?
軽い… 音楽？
That's right. The Light Music Club?
そう 軽い音楽
So, what's your plan, Ritsu?
で どうするの？
We wait for prospective members!
入部希望者を待つ
We just wait.
待つの？
Wait!
待つ！
うんッ
Come on, let's go home.
帰ろっか
Hello, I wanted to find out about joining your club.
あの～ 見学したいんですけど
おおッ
軽音部の？
The Light Music Club?
いえ 合唱部の
No, I'm at the Choir Club.
Why not join the Light Music Club instead?
軽音部に入りませんか？
But, the Choir Club...
あの 合唱部に
We need more members like you!
今 部員が少なくて
What?
Please! I'm begging you! You won't regret it, I promise!
お願いします 後悔は させません
Don't try to force her to join like that! It's really rude!
そんな強引な勧誘したら 迷惑だろッ
I'm going now. I'm sorry.
じゃあ 私も行くから
Mio!
澪ッ
What about that promise we made? Was that just a big lie?!
あのときの約束は…ウソだったのか！
That I would play drums! And then you would play the bass!
私がドラムで 澪がベースで
Our band! We've been saying forever that we would start one.
ずっと… ずっと 一緒にバンド組もうねって
We promised each other, remember?!
約束… してたじゃないッ
That night we went to see that concert together!
２人でライブに行った あの日
This is it.
これだ
This is, isn't it?
これ… だよね
Were those sweet words nothing but a big lie?!
あのときの言葉は ウソだったのかあ～ッ
No, your flashback is.
その回想がウソだ
What? Really it is?
ありッ そうだっけ？
Mio, this is it!
これだよ これッ
You and I are going to play in a band together! Is that exciting?!
バンドやろうよ バンド！
You forced the idea on me.
て 律が強引に
Yeah, but you said you wanted to!
澪も やるって言ったじゃん
Yes, I did, but...
そうだけど…
And if we went pro, we said we'd split all the proceeds 70/30!
それで プロになったら
ギャラは７：３ねって
Don't make stuff up.
ねつ造すんな
This will be a great deal of fun.
何だか 楽しそうですね
キーボードくらいしかできませんけど
The only instrument I can play is the keyboard,
私で よければ 入部させてください
but I'd like to join your club if you'll have me.
Thank you so much! Now we only need one more person to join us!
ありがとーう
これであと１人 入部すれば～
Well, I suppose that means I'm already a member.
私も もう人数に入ってるのね
Um, you're...
えっと～
Tsumugi Kotobuki.
琴吹紬です
I'm Ritsu Tainaka, drums. This is Mio Akiyama, she's on bass.
ドラムの田井中律
こっちはベースの秋山澪
うん あとは…
Let's see... Now we need a guitar player!
ギターだな！
Yui?
唯？
My high school years are very important. I wanna do something...
せっかく高校に入ったんだもん
何か したいよね
Well, then do it.
うん すれば
But I have absolutely no idea what it is I should do!
でも 何したらいいか分かんないんだよ～
Oh, good grief...
やれやれ
Would you like any french fries with that, Miss?
ご一緒に ポテトも いかがですか？
Yes! I would love some. Thank you.
はい お願いいたします
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
What is it?
どした？
私 ファーストフードのお店 初めてで
This is my first time eating in a fast food restaurant!
How can that be?
そうなの!?
I know it's silly but I've always dreamed of having someone ask me if I wanted french fries.
「ご一緒にポテトも いかがですか？」って言われるの
あこがれてたんです
Oh, I'm sorry. Please begin the meeting.
すみません 始めてください
'Kay, this meeting's come to order!
よし 作戦会議 開始！
Our goal is to recruit one more member by the end of the month!
今月中に 部員をあと１人 獲得するために
How in the world do we do that?
一体 何を？
That's why we're meeting to think of a way right now!
それをこれから考えるのさあ
今 入部したら
For instance, offering people an amazing prize if they decide to join!
何か すんごい特典もらえるとか
An amazing prize?
特典…
Yeah. Like some kind of gift or something.
そう 何か もらえるとか
Like a car or a plane or a boat?
車とか 別荘… とかですか？
Amazing but impractical.
すごいけど 無理
More along the lines of ice cream or help with homework.
アイス おごるとか
宿題 手伝うとか
Who would join up for something like that?
そんなことで入部するとは…
What should we do, then?
じゃあ どうしたら
Nyororin...
ニョロリ～ン
The president shouldn't lose interest!
自分が飽きて どうする
Come up with something to keep me interested.
じゃあ 何か考えてよ～
あッ もう帰りたい
I wanna go home.
Um, for now, why don't we...
あの～ とりあえず…
One, two!
せ～の
Poster: Light Music Club - Don't you want to join a band?
There's... there's just one more week remaining in April.
もう４月も あと１週間
No one's answered our ads yet.
誰も来てくれませんね
Disbanded before we are a band.
バンドも組めずに廃部か
I won't let that happen!
それは絶対 イヤーッ！
Wait, Light Music, huh?
軽…音楽か
Here, my click, clack, click, clack, here, ha, hi, is a click...
You're very good at that, Yui.
唯ちゃん 上手ね
I'm gonna do it!
よしッ
けいおん！
For the time being, I have decided to join the Light Music Club!
とりあえず 軽音楽部ってところに入ってみました
Oh, yeah? So, what is it that they do at this club?
で どんなことするの？
I don't know.
さあ？
Huh?
But since the name of the club is "light music," I figured they only do really easy stuff.
でも 軽い音楽って書くから
きっと簡単なことしか やらないよ
口笛とか
You know like whistling.
Sounds like they don't have much ambition.
何 その やる気のないクラブ
ほら 何かバンドとか するみたいだよ
You see? It looks like they're some kind of band.
What? But I don't know how to play the guitar!
私 ギターなんて弾けないよ
じゃあ 何なら弾けるの？
Well then, what can you play?
I can play castanets.
カッ カスタネット
Uh, click, fu, clack, fu, click...
That's a perfect fit for you.
すごく似合うわ
See? Look at this here...
ほら これがさ
なあ あんたねッ
What's with that?
Good afternoon.
こんにちは
こんにちは～
A prospective member has come forward.
入部希望者がいたわよ
Here. Isn't that wonderful news?
よかったわね
Also that's a lovely tea set, but make sure you clean up after yourselves once you're done, all right?
それと ステキなティーセットだけど
飲み終わったら ちゃんと片づけてね
All right!
は～い
Yes! Now we won't be disbanded!
ヨッシャー 廃部じゃなくなる～
Yui Hirasawa...
平沢唯
Just her name makes her sound really awesome!
何か名前から すごそうだぞ
She's got to be a guitarist.
やっぱ ギターだよな
I can't wait to meet her.
楽しみですねえ
Yeah! A real powerhouse has joined us!
すっご～い 強力なメンバー 加入～！
Light music club...
軽音部 軽音部？
Light music club?
こッ ここを抜けないと
If I don't get down this hallway, I won't reach the Light Music Club!
軽音部に たどりつけない
Oh, hello.
あらッ
The Light Music Club is up in the Music Room.
軽音楽部なら 音楽室よ
Sign: Music Room
This is the place?
ここか…
It won't be an easy thing to say right after joining, but I've got to quit.
入ったばっかで言いにくいけど
やっぱり やめるって言おう
I wonder what kind of people would join a Light Music Club?
でも 軽音部って どんな人が いるのかなあ
Oh, you want to quit, do you?
ああん やめたいだと？
Did you think you could walk away without any consequences?!
キサマ ただでやめられると思ってるのか
I'll murder you!
さつがいするぞ～
What am I gonna do?!
どうしよう…
あの あの
ち ちッ 違います 違います…
You've got it all wrong!
What? It's the useless clumsy bad tempo girl!
テンポ悪くて使えないドジっ子
What is it you're doing?
何やってるの？
You startled me.
ビックリした
もしかして あなたが平沢唯さん？
You are Yui Hirasawa by any chance?
Y-Yes.
はッ はい
The girl who wants to join us?
入部希望の
Uh, yes.
はッ はい
I'm so sorry I misjudged you! I'm sure you must be totally awesome on guitar!
いろいろ誤解してて ごめん
ギターがすっごく うまいんだよね
We've all been waiting for you to get here!
来てくれるの待ってたよ～
It seems like someone's been embellishing things about me...
何か あらぬ尾ヒレが ついてるよ
Hey, guys! Our brand-new member has arrived!
みんな～入部希望者が来たぞ～
Is that her?
本当か
Aha!
まあ
Welcome to the Light Music Club!
ようこそ 軽音部へ
歓迎いたしますわ～
It's so good to have you here!
Right! Mugi, go get the tea ready!
よ～し ムギ お茶の準備だ
Okay.
はい
What should I do?
どッ どうしよう
Go ahead, it's quite delicious.
どうぞ 召し上がって
Wow, this is great!
おいしい
This is so good!
おいし～い
やめるの やめようかな
Maybe I should give up on trying to quit...
What kind music do you like to play?
平沢さんは どんな音楽 やりたいの？
Who's your all time favorite band?
どんなバンドが好きか
Which guitarists do you like?
好きなギタリストは？
えっと…
Oh my... I have to tell them. I can't really play the guitar at all!
やっぱ言わなきゃ
実は ギターなんて弾けないって
J... J... J...
じ じ じ…
Are you trying to say Jimi Hendrix?!
ジミ·ヘンドリックス？
Wow.
おお～
No, it's not. I mean, I don't...
いッ いえ～
じ じ…
Jimmy Page, then?!
ジミー·ペイジ？
No! Oh, no, I ju... ju...
違ッ じ…
Wow.
ああ～ッ
Jeff Beck?!
ジェフ·ベック？
Are there really this many guitarists whose names start with "J"?!
ギタリストって 「じ」で始まる人 多いの？
Oh, wow, Jeff Beck, that's cool!
そっか～ ジェフ·ベックかあ
Who is he?
どなた？
In the music world, they say that there's only two kind of rock guitarists: Jeff Beck, and everyone else.
ロックギタリストには２種類しかいない
ジェフ·ベックとジェフ·ベック以外だっていわれている
He's a brilliant and challenging guitarist who's always searching for new sounds.
常に 新しいサウンドを追求する 挑戦的なギタリスト
My goodness.
まあ
You're so hardcore, Miss Hirasawa!
さっすが～シブイねえ 平沢さん
I gotta say I'm so glad that someone like her joined the club.
平沢さんみたいな人が入ってくれて よかったな
We were at the point where the club would have been disbanded if we hadn't gotten another member within the next week.
１週間以内にあと１人 集まらなかったら
廃部になるところだったんです
Thank you so much for joining!
ほんっとに ありがと～う
They keep making it harder!
ますます言いづらいよ
But I'm... I'm just going to have to spit it out!
でも ちゃんと言わなきゃ
あのッ あの
I'm really sorry, I don't know how to say it if I made a mistake joining this club but I only came here to beg you to let me quit!
申し訳ないんですけど
実は 入部するのやめさせてくださいって 言いにきたんです
えッ？
What?
ギターは弾けないし
I can't play the guitar.
I thought you would be playing a different kind of instrument.
もっと違う楽器をやるんだと思って
What instrument can you play, then?
じゃあ 何ならできるの？
Casta... Er, the harmonica.
カスタ… ハッ ハーモニカ
Oh, I have a harmonica right here. Try playing something!
あッ ハーモニカならあるよ
吹いてみて
I'm sorry, I can't play it!
ごめんなさい 吹けません
But, Miss Hirasawa, if you wanted to join this club, that means that you're at least interested in music, right?
でも ウチの部に入ろうと思ったってことは
音楽には興味あるってことよね
Is there another club you'd rather join?
他に入りたい部とか あるの？
No, none in particular.
ううん 特には
We can't let this mark leave this room no matter what!
せっかくのカモを ここで手放すわけにはいかないぜ
To keep the club from being disbanded...
廃部を免れるために
We have to keep her here somehow!
何とか 引き止めないと
I'm sorry, I really mean it. Bye.
本当に ごめんなさい じゃあ…
Wait just a minute!
ちょっと待って
How about another cup of tea?
もう一杯 お茶いかが？
But I...
でも…
We have cookies and madeleines as well.
クッキーとマドレーヌもあるの
Mm-hm.
They're baiting the hook!
餌付けた…
So good... I-I'm sorry, I didn't mean to come here and gorge myself.
おいし～い
す すみません
こんなにごちそうになるつもりじゃ
Hey, don't sweat it!
いいの いいの
I think we should start eating snacks like this every day from now on.
毎日 こうやって 一緒に お菓子を食べましょう
Aren't we drifting off topic here... Ow!
何か趣旨が違ってきて… 痛ッ
Miss Hirasawa, what other sorts of things do you like?
平沢さん 他には どんなものが好き？
Oh, I like anything that tastes good.
おいしいものなら何でも
Geez, just food?
食べ物かよ
On your days off, do you spend your time at home doing anything in particular?
ウチでは 休みの日とか 何して過ごしてんの？
Just sitting around, I guess.
ゴロゴロ… かな
What kind of things do you like?
好きなものとか ある？
I like cute things, I guess.
カワイイものが好き かな
Have any weaknesses?
苦手なものは…
I'm not very good with extreme heat or cold.
暑いのも 寒いのも 苦手なんだ
冬は コタツにこもりっきりだし
I spend winter under the table where it's warm. And in the summer, I spend my time on the floor where it's cool.
夏は 床の上をころがってばっかりいるの
手ごわい
She's a tough one.
What the heck do we do?
一体 どうすれば…
I don't know.
分かりません
Um, I should go.
あ あの… じゃあ
Please, don't go, I'm begging you! You can just hang out and do nothing if you want!
あッ 行かないで お願い
ゴロゴロしてるだけで いいから
I'll try to bring even tastier snacks, okay?
もっと おいしいお菓子持ってきますから
I'm really sorry.
ごめんなさい 軽い気持ちで入部するなんて書いたから
I didn't take things seriously when I applied to join.
I got all your hopes up.
期待させるだけさせて 何て謝ったらいいかあ…
How can I ever apologize?
We're the ones who should apologize.
私達こそ ごめんなさい
We shouldn't have tried to force you to stay.
無理に引き止めて 悪かったな
じゃあ せめて 私達の演奏だけでも聴いていって
So please! At least hang around for a while and listen to us play a song!
You'll play a song for me?!
演奏してくれるの？
食いついてきた
She's swallowed the bait!
One, two, three, four!
ワン ツー スリー フォー
What did you think?
どうだった？
I don't know what to say...
何ていうか すごく言葉にしにくいんだけど
It's really hard to put into words!
うんッ
あんまりうまくないですね
You guys aren't very good, are you?
Talk about blunt!
バッサリだあ
But it seemed like it would be a whole lot of fun to do!
でも 何だか すっごく楽しそうでした
I decided that I'm going to join this club!
私 この部に入部します！
Banzai!
バンザ～イ
Excuse me.
ちょっと失礼
Okay, let's commemorate the start of the Light Music Club!
じゃあ 軽音部活動開始記念に！
Hey, that's my camera.
ああ 私のカメラ
Here we go, guys!
いっくよ～ん
But the problem is that I can't play any instruments at all.
あッ でも 私 全然楽器できないし
あッ マネージャーとか どうかなあ
Can I be a manager or something?
いや 運動部じゃないんだし
Well, we aren't a sports club.
I know, why don't you take this opportunity to begin learning the guitar?
そうだ この機会にギターを始めてみたら どうかしら
But it looks very complicated! I don't think I could...
でッ でも すごく難しそうな
Don't worry about it.
大丈夫だよ～
Between the three of us, we'll teach you everything you need to know.
私達も 分かるところは教えてあげるし
I guess you're right.
そうだね
Listening to you play just now made me feel like I can do at least that well, if not a lot better!
さっきの演奏聴いてたら
私にも できるかもって思えてきた
So glad to be of help.
…それは よかった
What? You went ahead and joined anyway?
えッ 結局 入部したんだ
う～ん どうしてもって言われて～
They practically begged me to join!
Seriously?!
マジで!?
Oh, as a manager or something, right?
ああ マネージャーとしてとかね
When someone else says it, it sounds insulting.
人に言われると 何か悔しい
I joined as a full-fledged member of the band.
ちゃんと メンバーとして入ったんだから
And they say they'll teach me to play guitar!
ギター イチから教えてくれるって
Oh, that means you're gonna have to go out and buy yourself a new guitar.
あッ ということは 新しくギター買ったりするんだ
うう～ん 貸してくれないのかなあ
I wonder if they'll let me borrow one?
Probably not.
くれないんじゃない？
You can buy them for about $50, right?
5000円くらいで買えるよね
こんな子 つかまされて
Oh, boy. I wonder if the Light Music Club knows what they're getting themselves into with this girl.
大丈夫かしら… 軽音部！
Please don't say you're lazy,
because you're actually crazy
The swans are actually
Please don't say“You are lazy”
だって本当はcrazy
白鳥達はそう　見えないところでバタ足するんです
kicking their legs hard
out
of sight
Being true and sincere to my instincts,
I accept that I'll
be tossed around
本能に従順 忠実　翻弄も重々承知
The path ahead looks bright
前途洋々だし…だからたまに休憩しちゃうんです
That's why I
take rests
sometimes
近道あればそれが王道　はしょれる翼もあれば上等
If there's a shortcut,
it's the best route
If I have wings to use, then it'll be the best
ヤバ 爪割れた　グルーで補修した
Crap, I broke a nail!
I'll fix it with glue
That's enough to give me
a sense of achievement
それだけでなんか達成感
大事なのは自分　かわいがること
What's important is to take good care of yourself
自分を愛さなきゃ　他人も愛せない
If you can't love yourself, then you can't love someone else
Please don't say“You are lazy”
Please
don't
say
you
are
because
you
are
actually
だって本当はcrazy
Skilled
hawks
能ある鷹はそう　見えないとこにピック隠すんです
hide their talons
out of sight
I try to use my imagination,
想像に一生懸命　現実は絶体絶命
but reality is a bitch
I'm still just learning,
発展途中だし…だから不意にピッチ外れるんです
so I'll be out of pitch sometimes
Next Episode
Hey, everyone! These three are my fellow Light Music Club members.
こんにちは
この３人が軽音部の仲間です
I wanted to pick a club where I could make friends with sort of fun, pleasant people that one so rarely meets.
めったに出会えない
とっても楽しくて 愉快な人達の仲間になりたかったの
Y-Yui...
ゆ… ゆい？
All right! Let's get to it!
よっしゃ やるぞ～
Go!
Oh! Hey, guys!
あッ みんな
痛ッ
Now that I finally made it to high school.
高校生になった私は初めて…
I've joined a club for the first time!
Instrument!
部活を始めました！